see see merry good okay so I'm Ron
看到快活好吧，所以我是罗恩
Pressler technical lead for Project loon
Project Loon的Pressler技术主管
obviously I'm gonna be talking about
显然我会在谈论
that today but also a bit about how over
今天，还有一点关于如何结束
JDK projects are happen
JDK项目正在发生
I call this talk practically one year in
我说这个演讲大约一年
the projects actually a bit older I'll
这些项目实际上会有点老
explain why it's exactly actually from
解释为什么它实际上是从
my perspective one year in first as Mark
我第一年的观点是Mark
Ronald says I work for Oracle's so
罗纳德说我为甲骨文公司工作
everything I'm gonna say is a lie but
我要说的只是谎言，但
first a refresher for if they're some of
首先，如果他们是一些
you who don't know what Lou maze or I've
不知道我是楼迷宫的人
forgotten just why we're doing this so
忘记了我们为什么要这样做
the goal is to make concurrent programs
目标是制作并发程序
easier to write today programmers are
今天更容易写程序员
basically faced with a binary choice
基本上面临二元选择
they can either write simple blocking
他们可以编写简单的阻止
code for example like servlets where you
例如servlet之类的代码
have you run a request start to finish
您是否已开始执行请求
in a single thread and the code is nice
在一个线程中，代码很不错
the problem is that modern operating
问题是现代操作
systems can manage them far larger
系统可以管理更大的系统
number of open TCP sockets than they can
打开的TCP套接字数超出限制
run active threads so that's a
运行活动线程，所以这是一个
scalability bottleneck what other people
可伸缩性瓶颈
are doing they care more about
在做他们更在乎
scalability so the write code that's
可扩展性，因此编写代码
very scalable but they use asynchronous
可扩展性很强，但它们使用异步
code with callbacks or completable
带回调或可填充的代码
future or something like arts Java or
未来或类似艺术Java或
akka all the other asynchronous
akka所有其他异步
frameworks so it is scalable but the
框架，因此可扩展，但是
code is generally more complex more
代码通常更复杂
importantly it's much harder to debug
重要的是，调试起来要困难得多
it's nearly impossible to profile and it
这几乎是不可能的，它
is pretty much downright impossible to
完全是不可能的
interoperate with existing blocking code
与现有的阻止代码互操作
it's very you can't mix the two so you
非常不能将两者混在一起
either block or you don't it's very hard
要么阻止，要么就不困难
to mix a synchronous and asynchronous
混合同步和异步
code so we want to take this binary
代码，所以我们要使用此二进制文件
choice away
选择离开
and basically the idea is that threads
基本上，这个想法是线程
are very simple it's it's a good
非常简单，这是一个很好的
abstraction but their implementation in
抽象，但它们的实现
the OS is insufficient for the
操作系统不足以
requirements we have so we just make
我们有要求，所以我们只需
more threads and instead of relying on
更多线程，而不是依赖
the operating system to manage them
操作系统来管理它们
because it cans for various reasons we
因为它可以出于各种原因
have threads in the runtime we call them
在运行时中有线程，我们称它们为
those are lightweight threads we call
这些是我们称之为轻量级的线程
them fibers I may refer to them as
他们纤维我可以称他们为
lightweight threads as well and you can
轻量级线程也可以
have as many as you want and the reason
有你想要的数量和原因
that makes that makes coding easier is
使编码更容易的是
that now there is a natural translation
现在有一个自然的翻译
from the internet of concurrency of the
从并发的互联网
application which is a session or
会话或
request or user or maybe an outgoing
请求或用户，或者外向
request to the software unit of
要求软件部门
concurrency which is the thread so it
并发性是线程，所以
can be a one-to-one mapping which makes
可以是一对一的映射
writing the code a lot easier so from
编写代码要容易得多，因此从
the perspective of the user the users
用户的视角用户
gonna be writing ordinary simple
会写普通的简单
blocking code but that's not what the
阻止代码，但这不是
operating system is gonna see the
操作系统会看到
operating is gonna see only very few
操作只会看到很少
kernel threads and if you use if you do
内核线程，如果使用，请使用
any i/o operation so from the
任何I / O操作
perspective programmer is gonna look
透视程序员会看起来
like blocking i/o but from the
就像阻止I / O，但是
perspective of the operating system it's
操作系统的角度来看
gonna get translated automatically to
会自动翻译成
asynchronous i/o so you get the same
异步I / O，因此您获得相同的结果
scalability benefits of asynchronous
异步的可伸缩性优势
code but the convenience and
代码，但方便和
maintainability benefits of synchronous
同步的可维护性优势
code and rather than just so one of the
代码，而不仅仅是其中之一
reasons gonna make we hope writing
我们希望写的理由
concurrent programs easier is not just
并发程序更容易不仅仅是
by having as many threads as you like
通过拥有尽可能多的线程
but also helping you weave them together
而且还可以帮助您将它们编织在一起
into a sort of a coherent whole and this
成为一个连贯的整体
is a very recent work I'm gonna get
是我将要获得的最新作品
around to later ok so
到以后再好吧
the first thing that has changed since I
自从我改变了第一件事
was here last year is that now we have a
去年在这里是现在我们有一个
party site that you can try and run just
您可以尝试运行的派对网站
go there some people are already already
去那里已经有人了
playing with this and also if you have
玩这个，如果你有
any questions so you can ask me so
有什么问题可以问我
please ask me during the talk maybe I'll
请在谈话中问我，也许我会
tell you that's the question for later
告诉你这是以后的问题
but just try to ask well I'm talking so
但是试着问好我在说
really project flume was first discuss a
真正的项目水槽首先是讨论
JVM less so it's around August 2017 and
JVM较少，因此大约在2017年8月，
then apparently the process is that
那么显然过程是
you're supposed to go around it's more
你应该去周围更多
helpful if it's Oracle because that's
如果是Oracle，会很有帮助，因为那是
where most people are to go internally
大多数人在内部去的地方
inside Oracle and find people who want
在Oracle内部并找到想要的人
to work on it that seem pretty strange
看起来很奇怪
to me at first but that's the process
一开始对我来说就是这样
and the very first person right at JVM
也是JVM的第一人称
less who wanted to join the project was
较少想参加该项目的人是
Alan Bateman so he's sort of co-leading
艾伦·贝特曼（Alan Bateman）所以他有点共同领导
it with me and he's doing most of the
和我在一起，他正在做大部分
API design library work and so they're
API设计库可以正常工作
back there we didn't even have a name
回到那里，我们甚至都没有名字
Brian gets came up with the name I think
Brian想出了我想的名字
a day later and so we already had like
一天后，所以我们已经喜欢
two people and name the announcement to
两个人，并将公告命名为
the open JDK mailing list came shortly
打开的JDK邮件列表很快出现了
afterwards but it took it's a it's a
之后，但是花了一个
process so I took I think until October
过程，所以我想直到十月
until was actually an official project
直到实际上是一个官方项目
October 2017 and at that time Allen
2017年10月，当时艾伦
already started working on the libraries
已经开始在图书馆工作
there was nothing yet in the VM but
虚拟机中什么都没有，但是
started working on the libraries getting
开始致力于图书馆
the i/o ready for all that stuff well I
我为所有这些东西做好了准备
was thinking about how to implement
在考虑如何实施
continuations so fibers are implemented
连续性，使纤维得以实施
on top of a more basic primitive in the
在最基本的原语之上
VM that's called continuation is going
称为延续的虚拟机正在运行
to get right to it and the VM gives you
正确使用它，VM会给您
continuations and the fibers are
延续和纤维是
implemented in top of them in the
在它们的顶部实现
libraries
图书馆
so I had sort of an idea on how to do it
所以我对如何做有个想法
first let me show you what it looks like
首先让我告诉你它的样子
so this is a very partial part of the
所以这是
API a continuation is basically like a
API的延续基本上就像
runnable let's get back to it in a
可运行的让我们回到它
moment so it's like a runnable it
那一刻，它就像是可运行的
doesn't have any any notion of running
没有任何跑步的概念
things in parallel but it's a special
事情并行，但这是一个特殊的
kind of runnable so it runs in line with
一种可运行的，因此它与
your code you you call it and runs in
您调用的代码并在其中运行
line so nothing in parallel but it's
行，所以没有什么并行的，但是
special in the following way
通过以下方式特殊
a runnable runs you start running it
可运行的运行您开始运行它
runs to completion and then returns to
运行到完成，然后返回
the caller continuations can call a new
呼叫者继续可以呼叫新
operation called yield and when a
操作称为yield，当
continuation does a yield it returns
延续会产生收益
through the call it returns to the
通过通话返回到
caller and the next time the
来电者，下次
continuation is run instead of starting
连续运行而不是开始
in the beginning it continues from the
从一开始它就继续
yield point so continuations are very
屈服点，所以延续非常
very low-level you're not supposed
很低级的你不应该
developers are not gonna use them
开发人员不会使用它们
directly you can use constructs are
直接你可以使用构造
built on top of them higher level
建立在它们之上
constructs one of them is fibers but if
构造其中之一是纤维，但如果
you were to use them you do them like
你会使用它们，就像
this you create a continuation I'll
这会创建一个延续
explain what the scope is and then let's
解释范围是什么，然后让我们
say you have this infinite loop that
说你有这个无限循环
occasionally yields and so this is your
偶尔会有收益，所以这是你的
sort of runnable continuation and then
某种可运行的延续，然后
you way the way you run it is as long as
您的运行方式只要
it's not done it's going to be done when
它没有完成，它将在何时完成
the that runnable has actually
那可运行的实际上
terminated but as long as it's not done
终止，但只要未完成
you're going to run it again and every
您将要再次运行它
time you run it it's going to continue
你运行它的时间将会继续
at the yield point a couple of important
在屈服点，几个重要的
points here this yield in this case it
在这种情况下指出这里的产量
is actually in the top-level lambda
实际上是在顶级Lambda中
expression but it can be deep in the
表达，但它可以深入人心
sack so you can be nested in some some
麻袋，所以你可以嵌套在一些
other method and the scope that
其他方法和范围
mysterious scope parameter that is what
神秘的范围参数是什么
allows us to nest multiple continuations
允许我们嵌套多个延续
inside one another and when you yield on
彼此相处，当你屈服于
a certain scope it basically tells you
基本上可以告诉您的一定范围
which of the callers to return true kind
哪个调用者返回真实的类型
of like throwing an exception with
就像抛出一个异常
multiple handlers so you can go back so
多个处理程序，因此您可以返回
when you yield you can go back to the
当你屈服时，你可以回到
immediately enclosing can he
立即将其围起来
or if you're inside several
或者如果你在几个里面
continuations you can jump to the one
延续，你可以跳到一个
you return to the caller that created
您返回到创建的呼叫者
the continuation with that scope so this
该范围的延续，所以这
is the a part of the API so we have the
是API的一部分，因此我们拥有
constructor we have run we have is done
我们已经运行的构造函数已经完成
and yield that's what we saw and right
而产量就是我们所看到的，正确的
at the beginning so even almost here
一开始甚至几乎在这里
last year we knew that we're gonna have
去年我们知道我们会
some technical limitations one of them
一些技术限制之一
is that so the continuation when you
是这样，当你继续
yield it must remember its state so next
屈服它必须记住它的状态，所以接下来
time when you run it it it has to know
您运行它的时间，它必须知道
where to continue and you can be several
在哪里继续，你可以是几个
methods deep so part of that state is a
方法很深，所以该状态的一部分是
stack so a continuation needs to
堆叠，因此需要延续
remember the stack and we wanted to move
记住堆栈，我们想移动
stacks around and that is something that
堆放着，那是
you cannot do if you have native frames
如果您有原生框架，您将无法做
so basically a continuation has its own
所以基本上延续有自己的
stack and when you run it we say that
堆栈，当您运行它时，我们说
you mount the continuation so
您安装延续，所以
conceptually you can think of it as if
从概念上讲，您可以将其视为
you take the continuation stack and
你拿延续栈，
append it to the thread stack and when
将其附加到线程堆栈以及何时
you yield or unmount it you take that
你屈服或卸下它
portion of the stack and move it to the
堆栈的一部分并将其移至
side so if you happen to have a native
因此，如果您碰巧有一个本地人
frame on the continuation stack for
连续堆栈上的框架
example you are inside a continuation
例如，你在延续中
then you call out to J and I from J now
那你现在就叫J和J
you called back in to Java and then you
您回叫到Java，然后您
do a yield so you have a native frame on
做一个收益，所以你有一个原生框架
the stack in that case we say the
在那种情况下，我们说
continuation is pinned it cannot be
延续被固定，不可能
yielded and when that happens when you
屈服，当你发生这种情况时
try to yield then this method is going
尝试让出这种方法
to be called which by default throws an
被调用，默认情况下会抛出一个
exception fibers do something else so we
异常纤维还有其他作用，所以我们
knew about that limitation even last
直到最后才知道这个限制
year when I was here so this is what we
我在这里的那一年，所以这就是我们
had but this is a slide to show you see
有，但是这是一张幻灯片，向您展示
the styling is different this is the
样式是不同的是
side I showed here last year so the
去年我在这里展示的一面
requirements are that we're gonna need
要求是我们将需要
millions of continuations and that means
数百万的延续，这意味着
that the footprint of each continuation
每个延续的足迹
must be very low and we need a very fast
必须非常低，我们需要非常快
task switching so we can we can mount
任务切换，以便我们可以挂载
and unmount continuations very quickly
并快速卸载连续
and I said that conceptually you can
我说从概念上讲
think of it as if taking the
想起来好像
sack of the continuation appending it to
将其附加到的麻袋
the thread so we thought okay so if that
线程，所以我们认为还可以，如果
must be very fast we shouldn't do any
一定非常快，我们不应该做任何事情
copying so it's just conceptual copying
复制，所以这只是概念性复制
but the easiest thing to do was just
但是最简单的事情就是
point the stack pointer to wherever the
将堆栈指针指向
continuation stack is and I showed you a
延续堆栈是，我给你看了一个
whole thing of how to do it here at Jay
杰伊在这里如何做的全部事情
focus and the very next day the so here
重点，第二天就这样
in the Stockholm office there are a lot
在斯德哥尔摩办公室有很多
of the GC people and they basically told
的GC人员，他们基本上告诉
us that this cannot be done and actually
我们，这是不可能做到的，实际上
John Rose was here and both he and I
约翰·罗斯（John Rose）在这里，他和我
were kind of depressed about this for a
对此感到沮丧
few days and so what I mean by cannot be
几天，所以我的意思不可能是
done can be done wouldn't you know under
完成可以完成，你不知道下
a few years of work another slide I
几年的工作我另一张幻灯片
showed you we had some ideas of where to
向您展示了我们对去哪里有一些想法
store the continuations stack either on
将延续堆栈存储在
the Java heap or some some parts of the
Java堆或
C heap and also we didn't know back then
C堆，那时候我们也不知道
if we were to store the configuration
如果我们要存储配置
stack on the heap there we had two
堆在堆上，我们有两个
options of how to do it either maintain
如何做到的选择要么保持
the same layout of the stack as it is
堆栈的布局与原样相同
normally for threads and but then it
通常用于线程，但随后
means that the references or what we
意味着参考或我们
call in hotspots oops can be anywhere on
热点呼唤可以在任何地方
the stack so we need to have an OOP map
堆栈，所以我们需要一个OOP映射
to tell the GC the the various tree
告诉GC各种树
season how it's about where to find
到哪里寻找季节
their hoops and the other was to
他们的篮球，另一个是
separate the primitives and the
分离基元和
references to different rays so after a
引用不同的射线，所以
lot of discussions literally the next
从字面上来看很多讨论
day after I gave the talk they also said
我讲完演讲后的第二天，他们还说
that that couldn't be done
那是无法做到的
so we've decided to go with this and I
所以我们决定去这个，我
said we were very sad that we couldn't
说我们很伤心，因为我们不能
do it without copying so you said okay
不用复制就做，所以你说好
let's do copying and and figure it out
让我们复制并弄清楚
later
后来
so this is how in the current prototype
所以这就是目前的原型
initiations were
启蒙是
it starts with copying but then I'll
它从复制开始，但是我会
show you a cool trick that we came up
告诉你一个很酷的技巧，我们来了
with so let's say this is a native sack
这么说，这是一个本地麻袋
this is the ordinary thread stack you
这是普通的线程堆栈
call run on the continuation and you now
呼叫继续运行，您现在
enter the continuation you're gonna
输入您要继续的
internally there is an internal
内部有一个内部
continuation method called enter and
继续方法称为enter和
then it's gonna run your runnable and
然后它将运行您的可运行的
those would be the frames and eventually
这些将是框架，最终
you want to call yield so when you call
你想打电话给收益，所以当你打电话
yield it's gonna call into the VM and to
让它进入虚拟机并
a native method in the VM called freeze
VM中的本机方法称为“冻结”
and what freeze is going to do is going
冻结将要进行
to start copying the frames to the
开始将框架复制到
continuation stack that's stored on the
存储在
ordinary Java heap so it's going to copy
普通的Java堆，因此它将被复制
this frame and then so while it's
这个框架，然后虽然它是
copying also has to examine whether the
复制还必须检查
the frame is for example a native one I
例如，框架是本机框架
know which case you're pinned and if it
知道您固定在哪种情况下，如果
isn't it's gonna continue copying them
是不是要继续复制它们
so first it copies the continuation as
所以首先将延续复制为
is with all the references inside into
与所有引用一起进入
the so stack is the primitive array and
所以堆栈是原始数组，
ref stack is the reference array that's
引用堆栈是
the object array and then it extracts
对象数组，然后提取
loops from that frame and copies them to
从该帧循环并复制到
the reference stack and it does that for
参考堆栈，它为
all the frames one thing I forgot to
所有帧我忘了一件事
change the slides that we recently
更改我们最近的幻灯片
changed so I showed how it copies so
改变了，所以我展示了它是如何复制的
this called the top of the stack how it
这叫做栈顶
copies from the top of the stack down
从堆栈顶部向下复制
actually now we change the order to
实际上，现在我们将订单更改为
copies them in the other direction
将它们复制到另一个方向
but the same idea and then freeze is
但相同的想法然后冻结
gonna jump back to run and that's it and
要跳回去跑了，就是这样
when we want to continue the
当我们想继续
continuation the next time we call run
下次我们称为运行继续
so recognizes the continuation already
所以已经认识到延续
has some internal state so it calls
有一些内部状态，所以它调用
enter again but now recognizes that
再次输入，但现在意识到
there is something there so it's going
那里有东西，所以要去
to call something called to continue and
打电话叫继续
that is going to copy the frames it's
将要复制的帧
going to make some room on the stack and
将在堆栈上腾出一些空间，
it copies
它复制
the frames in the other direction so
框架在另一个方向上
first it copies the frame as is it
首先它照原样复制框架
restores the hoops to the right place
将箍恢复到正确的位置
because the the GCS may have moved the
因为GCS可能已经移动了
objects around and as long as they're on
周围的物体，只要它们在
the objects act that GC knows where to
GC知道在哪里进行操作的对象
find them and if they're relocated it
找到他们，如果他们已经搬迁了
fixes all the pointers so we have to
修复所有指针，所以我们必须
restore them to to their new values and
将它们恢复到新值，并
we also have to patch the frame so that
我们还必须修补框架，以便
some sort of metadata on each of the
每个上的某种元数据
frames to make sure that they know how
框架以确保他们知道如何
to return to the right place and we do
回到正确的地方，我们做
that to the rest of the frames and then
其余的帧，然后
we return and to yield so the conceptual
我们返回并屈服，所以概念
idea of copying the frames portion of
复制框架部分的想法
the stack is actually what we're doing
堆栈实际上就是我们在做什么
however that is not what we wanted to do
但是那不是我们想要做的
we didn't want to copy anything and the
我们不想复制任何东西，
problem with this is is the following
这是下面的问题
let's say you have the cost of this is
假设您为此付出的代价是
linear in the depth of the stack that
堆叠深度呈线性关系
you have it is very much possible that
你很有可能
you'll be like 100 methods deep in a
你会像一个深处的100种方法
very tight loop around yield but every
收益率非常紧密的循环，但每个
time you yield you have to copy those
当你屈服时，你必须复制那些
100 frames back and forth so the the
来回100帧
amount of work is linear in your total
总的工作量是线性的
depth of the stack and that is that can
堆栈的深度，那可以
be very bad so Eric do blood from the
非常糟糕，所以埃里克从
Stockholm wolf is here came up with an
斯德哥尔摩狼来了
idea and that was what we implemented in
这个想法，这就是我们在其中实施的
the prototype and that the idea is
原型，这个想法是
called lazy copy so the first time we
叫做懒惰副本，所以我们第一次
freeze or we yield the continuation we
冻结或我们产生延续我们
do the copying as I showed you but
按照我的指示进行复制，但是
that's only the first time next time we
这只是我们下次第一次
want to we want to continue the
想要我们想要继续
continuation what we're doing is we're
继续我们正在做的是
just going to copy so this is the same
只是要复制所以这是相同的
as before we're just gonna copy one or
和以前一样，我们只复制一个或
two frames so now this is a constant
两帧，所以现在这是一个常数
more or less a constant operation it's
或多或少的恒定操作
not dependent on the depth of the stack
不取决于堆叠的深度
we just copy one or two frames and then
我们只复制一两个框架，然后
what we do is that we change there
我们要做的是在那改变
turn address of this frame and replace
转到此框架的地址并替换
it with a pointer to a bit of code that
它带有指向一些代码的指针
we call the return barrier and if you
我们称之为回程壁垒，如果您
run and then we return to you
跑，然后我们回到你身边